<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>career on Random Walks</title>
    <link>https://algoexpt.github.io/tags/career/</link>
    <description>Recent content in career on Random Walks</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2022</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2022 01:49:43 +0900</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://algoexpt.github.io/tags/career/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Mass Goodbye Emails</title>
      <link>https://algoexpt.github.io/posts/massgoodbye/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2022 01:49:43 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://algoexpt.github.io/posts/massgoodbye/</guid>
      <description>This post originally appeared on LinkedIn. I have edited the text for readability
It&amp;rsquo;s common for employees who are leaving to send out a &amp;ldquo;Thank you and good bye&amp;rdquo; mail enmasse. Usually, this happens at Friday at 5:45 PM as everyone is winding down for the weekend.
Please don&amp;rsquo;t do this.
It&amp;rsquo;s a low effort call for attention. You feel on top of the world, your stress has evaporated, and you want to shout out your liberation from the rooftops.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Wall</title>
      <link>https://algoexpt.github.io/posts/will/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://algoexpt.github.io/posts/will/</guid>
      <description>Will Smith begins his biography, Will, with the story of his father demolishing a 12x20 feet wall. He asks Will, 11, and his younger brother Harry to rebuild it.
Will meets this decision with stupefaction:
I remember looking at that gaping hole in excruciating disbelief. I was utterly certain that there would never be a wall there ever again.
Will and his brother worked on the wall every day, mixing concrete and carrying the buckets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advice for young OR professionals</title>
      <link>https://algoexpt.github.io/posts/advice_for_or/advice-for-young-or-professionals/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 May 2021 16:48:33 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://algoexpt.github.io/posts/advice_for_or/advice-for-young-or-professionals/</guid>
      <description>Introduction I love mentoring young people, but I don’t get many chances to do so. In the last few years, some of my younger colleagues have asked me questions that I’ve not answered well.
I’ve had some time recently to think about what I would say if I had the opportunity to talk to them again. I’ve written down some of these thoughts. Like most advice, it is unsolicited, so what could be better than to put it out here and let anyone who can get value out of it do so?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
